Guide to the Preston Jones Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Professional Files, 1963-1986
  This series contains journals, address books, correspondence, contracts, royalty payments, articles, clippings and photographs. The major part of the material relates to A Texas Trilogy and is made up of communications with agents, fans, and theaters concerning options on the plays. Included is correspondence with Hal Wallis in regard to the movie production of the Trilogy.
  - Journals and address books, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Professional correspondence, A-U, 1974-1979 (Box 21, Folder 3-8)
  - Professional correspondence, V-Z, 1974-1979 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Empty files (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Preston and Mary Sue Jones' clipboards (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous writings by or about Preston Jones, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
  - Facts for resumes, Preston and Mary Sue Jones (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Jones and International Creative Management, 1974-1979 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - American Playwrights Theatre, contract and correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Wood, Baker and Dallas Theater Center contracts and correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Dramatists Guild, publications and correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Hill and Wang, Publishers, contracts and correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Royalty Payments, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Dramatist Play Service, correspondence, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Various Contracts, Mary Sue and Preston Jones, 1963-1986 (Box 23, Folder 7-10)
  - NBC/Graduate contracts and correspondence, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - American Place Theater, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Arena Theater and Alan Schneider, correspondence and newsletters, 1974-1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Texas Trilogy, photographs and negatives, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - JFK Center, correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Play outlines, cast descriptions, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Robert Whitehead Productions, correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - American Place Theater, contracts and correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Texas Commission on the Arts, correspondence and newsletters, 1975-1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Hal Wallis, correspondence, 1976, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Libraries, correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
  - Media, correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - P.E.N., an Association of Writers, letter, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Texas Institute of Letters, correspondence and newsletters, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - LBJ Library, includes correspondence with Lady Bird Johnson, other printed materials, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Theaters, correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
  - Universities, correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Audience and Fan response to plays with copies of Jones' replies, 1974-1979 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
- Publicity, 1974-1986
  This series contains materials on the promotion of Preston Jones' theatrical career especially in regard to the Trilogy. It includes photographs, clippings, reviews, articles, interviews and videotapes, providing information on aspects of the author's life, career, and writing methods.
  - Interview dress notes, checkbook, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Preston Jones and his sculptures, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Photos of Preston Jones, clippings, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - A Texas Trilogy reviews, programs, invitations (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Smithsonian, and photo proofs, October 1976 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Special issue of Time magazine, September 27, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Magazines featuring Preston Jones, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Articles, photographs, clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, clippings, photos, notes, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Articles, clippings, various printed materials, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Articles, clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: A Texas Trilogy, Hal Wallis, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Articles, reviews, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Articles, interviews, reviews, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Articles, reviews, 1976-1979 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - PBS tape, KERA, Dallas, original print (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Theatre Southwest, magazine and cassette tape, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Articles, news photos, correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Programs, certificate from governor of Alabama, articles, correspondence, 1975-1981 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Texas Committee for the Humanities radio spot and highband TV dub, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Essays about Preston Jones (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Articles, photos, correspondence, programs, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Articles, programs, costume designs, schedules, 1984-1986 (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Jones' Illness and Death, 1979-1983
  Jones died unexpectedly in September of 1979 after surgery for bleeding ulcers. This series contains documents concerning Jones' medical care and cause of death, obituaries, the funeral service, the memorial fund established at the Dallas Theater Center, sympathy cards, Christmas cards, acknowledgments from Mary Sue Jones, correspondence and reports on the estate.
  - Preston Jones' medical and death records, including concerns about malpractice and Preston and Mary Sue's will and testaments, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Articles on Preston Jones' death, September 1979 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Funeral service, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Clippings on death, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 4-8)
  - Photocopies of articles about Jones' death, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 9-11)
  - Preston Jones' Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1979-1981 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Mary Sue's correspondence relating to Preston and his work, 1976-1981 (Box 30, Folder 2-8)
  - Donations to Memorial Fund, 1980-1981 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Copies of typed thank-you letters, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous clippings related to Cable TV, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Get well cards and letters for Preston Jones, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Notebook on Preston Jones' Funeral, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Visitor's Book, Preston Jones' Funeral, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Flower cards, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Sympathy cards and letters, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 5-8, Box 32)
  - Sympathy cards, 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Theatre Southwest on Preston's death, October 1979 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Christmas cards, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
  - Malouf Lynch & Jackson, Attorneys at Law, estate file for Preston Jones, also past correspondence with firm, 1975-1983 (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Oversized Materials, undated
  This series contains World War I memorablia, material relating The Texas Trilogy, and personal items.
  - Two Army helmets, WWI paraphernalia, wooden fraternity paddle, New Mexico flag (Box 34)
  - WWI paraphernalia (knapsack, canvas gas mask kit), sports equipment (Box 35)
  - Personal items (pipes, glasses, coins, etc), Texas Trilogy memorabilia, sports equipment, Preston Jones' sculptures, part of Jones' teddy bear collection (Box 36)
  - Texas Trilogy memorabilia, Mary Sue Jones' personal items (key chains, teapot, paintings, etc.), props from various plays, part of Preston Jones' teddy bear collection (Box 37)
  - Duplicates of playbills, magazines, press clippings, and five plays: A Place on the Magdalena Flats, Remember, The Oldest Living Graduate, Santa Fe Sunshine, and Juneteenth (Box 38)
  - Duplicates of Plays (Box 39)
  - 2 sculptures made of wooden sticks (Box 40, Box 41)